# Michael Bade

1451 Sadler Dr. Apt. 1305 San Marcos, Texas 78666 (willing to relocate) 225-287-3847 | Email | Github | Blog | Portfolio

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full stack web developer with experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Studying Music Education and Opera gave me fantastic experience with learning syntax and attention to detail. After teaching an art form for several years, I'm excited to write meaningful code that makes a difference.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, React, Redux, Rails, Sinatra

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Vegan Camping Cookbook Collective - Github | Live Site

Designed for vegan outdoor enthusiasts to create a cookbook of their favorite camping recipes.

- Created a Single Page Application utilizing JS, HTML, and CSS on the frontend, and a Rails API backend.
- Engaged Fetch calls to the Rails API, which render and update the DOM based on event listeners.
- Employed Postgres on the backend for development and production.

# Doggo Play Date - Github | Live Site

The Doggo Playdate App is an app that allows users to make doggo playdates in the Austin, TX area.

- Ruby on Rails with an emphasis on MVC patterns.
- Utilized OAuth with the omniauth-facebook gem to log users in through Facebook.
- Users follow CRUD actions with ActiveRecord relationships in the backend.

## Mileage Tracker - Github | Live Site

Tracks the mileage and tracks all runs on your pairs of running shoes.

- Using a Sinatra framework, integrated PG Gem for production.
- Follows CRUD actions and implements MVC patterns.
- Runs validations on models, including the bcrypt gem to keep users' passwords secure.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Heart Support Developer**

Volunteer Developer

Austin, Texas 09/2020 - 10/2020

- Joined a group of volunteer developers for a 6-week sprint in "writing code that matters." We connected users on Facebook who are suffering from depression to the Heart Support discourse channel.
- Created a method which scrapes Facebook's API and registers a user in the HeartSupport database.
- Worked in a team with weekly stand ups and group collaboration across the world.

#### Jim Barnes Middle School

6th - 8th Grade Choir Teacher

Seguin, Texas 08/2017 - 05/2020

#### St. John's Lutheran Church

Director of Music

San Antonio, Texas 10/2018 - 09/2020

## **Hudson Middle School**

6th - 8th Grade Assistant Choir Teacher

Sachse, Texas 08/2016 - 05/2017

## **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School

Remote

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

05/ 2020 - 10/2020

**Louisiana State University** 

Baton Rouge, LA

Bachelor's in Music Education (3.55 GPA) & Master's of Music in Vocal Performance (3.95 GPA)

05/ 2016